Sachin yadav

 ♥ Bangalore City, India
 sachin11061997@gmail.com
 +917498549475
 in/sachin-yadav-web3/
 https://5achin.vercel.app/

SUMMARY

I am a certified blockchain developer and product development professional with 3+ years of experience working on blockchain projects, including leading my own web3.0 project, Gigaverse. My expertise includes creating interactive web applications using different tech skills also creating verified Solidity smart contracts and developing reliable Tokenomics structures. With technical skills in web development, Python scripting, and Solidity contracts, I am a solution–driven developer with strong background in inovative development and working with startups.

EXPERIENCE

Full Stack WEB3 Engineer

Platter Inc.

December 2022 - Present, Bangalore, India

- Demonstrated expertise in developing and deploying decentralized applications (dApps) using blockchain technologies, including creating smart contracts and integrating them into dApps to enable blockchain functionality.
- Designed and developed user interfaces for dApps using web3 libraries, integrated web3 wallets, and utilized decentralized storage solutions. Collaborated with designers and product managers to create user-centered experiences for dApps and integrated third-party APIs and services.
- · Developed server-side logic for dApps using back-end technologies and utilized DevOps tools and practices to deploy and manage the applications.

Product Developer

PhenomPeople Inc.

January 2022 - April 2022, Hyderabad,India

- · Conducted in-depth business discussions with senior management and provided key market data from various sources to inform business decisions.
- · Built charts and graphs to visualize data and met the operational data needs of the marketing team.
- $\cdot \text{Conducted thorough business analysis using tools such as MySql, Python, Beautiful soup, and Numpy to identify system connections and develop new bot scripts, procedures, and guidelines.}$

Full stack Developer

Gigaverse pvt. ltd.

July 2021 - December 2021, Pune, India

- · Managed and led technical product teams in the development and execution of protocol strategies, designs, and implementations.
- · Created bespoke bots to meet the specific needs of Gigaverse and its clients in defining and launching their instances of the protocol.
- · Facilitated goal setting, planning, retrospectives, and backlog grooming to ensure project milestones and objectives attained for website code and smart contracts.

PROJECTS

Platter Alpha Product

Platter Inc. December 2022 - Present

- \cdot Developed a portfolio DApp from scratch using MERN stack, providing an intuitive and user-friendly interface for users to manage their cryptocurrency portfolios.
- $\cdot \text{ Integrated multiple cryptocurrency exchanges and wallets into the DApp, enabling users to track their holdings across multiple platforms in one place.}$
- · Developed a backend API using Node.js and Express to fetch real-time market data and user account balances, optimizing the DApp for performance.

Python bots scripting

PhenomPeople pvt. ltd. • January 2022 - April 2022

- $\cdot \ \, \text{Developed several Telegram marketing bots under Gigaverse to automate customer conversion and connect them with relevant services.}$
- \cdot Utilized MS Excel-sheet with Python and Numpy embedded application to create the bots.
- · Implemented web scraping scripts to collect relevant WhatsApp data for targeted marketing using technologies like Selenium and Beautiful Soup (BS4).

Verified Smart contracts & CryptoCurrency Development

Gigaverse pvt. ltd. • August 2021 - December 2021

- · Developed and deployed a verified smart contract for virtual currency \$GIGS on the Binance Smart Chain with essential functionalities.
- · Integrated NFT candymachine using the Metaplex standard contracts for direct NFT listings with verified sources.
- $\cdot \ \, \text{Utilized Solidity and Remix IDE to develop secure contracts that met platform requirements}.$

INVOLVEMENT

President

Pune University • Entrepreneurship cell • January 2020 - January 2021

- · Led and organized "E-Conclave 2019," a successful large-scale event.
- · Collaborated with other leaders to plan and execute various aspects of the event.

EDUCATION

Bachelors of Engineering in Computer Science

Minor in information Technology · Pune University · Pune ,India · 2021 · 9.89 CGPA

SKILLS

Blockchain (Ethereum, Binance Smart Chain, Solana, zk rollups), Smart contracts (Solidity, Vyper), Web3 (Web3.js, Ethers.js), Decentralized storage (IPFS, Arweave), Stack (MERN /MEAN /LAMP), Frontend (HTML, CSS, JAVASCRIPT, React.js, Vue.js, Typescript, Angular), Backend (Node.js, Express), Databases (MongoDB, MySQL, PostgreSQL), DevOps (Docker, Kubernetes, AWS, GCP, Azure), 3D Render(Three.js, D3.js)